CARLOS NETO

DEVOPS ENGINEER

carlos.neto.dev@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c-neto/

https://github.com/augustoliks

Prazil - São Paulo

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Ownership mindset IT professional, with tech skills in Programming, Documentation, and DevOps.

It is a Python programming specialist, with experience in Amazon Web Services, especially in system provisioning, automation scripts, and managing logs pipelines and observability stacks.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

DevOps Engineer

Trustly Inc. | Online Banking Payments

Movember 2021 - Current

Remote

DevOps Engineer focused on Cloud programming demands. Responsible for automation development and Cloud components configuration in a world system-wide online banking platform.

Tasks Roadmap:

- Automation scripts with Python and Bash;
- OpenSearch Cluster Administration;
- Logstash Log Pipelines;
- AWS Resources Analysis and Configuration;
- Knowledge Base Documentation.

Software Developer

Fotosensores | Speed Camera Systems

April, 2018 - October, 2021

♀ On-site

Software Developer focused on In-House infrastructure demands. Responsible for microservices development, system provisioning, and observability in a regional system-wide Speed Camera System.

Tasks Roadmap:

- Python Microservices, scripts, and integrations;
- GitLab CI/CD Pipelines;
- Observability and Monitoring with Zabbix, Prometheus, and Grafana;
- Linux Servers administration and packing (CentOs based);
- Knowledge Base Documentation.

PROJECTS

- **SFTP Cluster (Trustly Inc.)**: High available SFTP Server with users setup provisioned by Ansible and deployed over Kubernetes;
- OpenSearch RBAC (Trustly Inc.): RBAC roles provisioned by OpenSearch Security Plugin based on Principle of Least Privilege;
- Image Transmissions Module (Fotosensores): Speed camera systems module to send vehicle images with integrity and cryptography built.
- Speed Camera Monitoring System (Fotosensores): Web system focused on speed camera system components observability.

EDUCATION

Analisys and Development System (High-Education)

FATEC - São José dos Campos

July 2016 - July 2019

Computer Network (Full-Certified)

ETEC - Cônego José Bento

February 2016 - July 2017

Industrial Automation (Full-Certified)
ITJ - Instituto de Tecnologia de Jacareí

February 2013 - December 2015

- GitLab Certified Associate Gitlab Inc;
- Python Formation Certified Alura;
- Fluent Pyhon Book.

SKILLS

ProgrammingPython Bash

• Cloud AWS

• CI/CD

GitLab CI/CD Github Actions

TravisCI

Observability and Monitoring

Grafana Zabbix Prometheus Loki

Containers

Kubernetes Docker Podman

Infrastructure as a Code

Ansible Terraform

Messaging

RabbitMQ ZeroMQ Redis

• Logs Pipeline

Logstash | Rsyslog | Promtail